Jimmy Baynes Collection (Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum Collection) ARC.0161
Library and Archives
Jimmy Baynes Collection (Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum Collection)
Bulk, 1955-1966
1953-1983
ARC.0161
Library and Archives
0.83 Linear feet (2 Hollinger boxes)
The Jimmy Baynes Collection (Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum Collection) spans the years 1953 to 1983 and includes some undated materials, with the bulk of the collection materials falling between the years 1955 and 1966. The Jimmy Baynes Collection is arranged into eight series by content: Jimmy Baynes, artists, distributors, radio stations, venues, unidentified individuals, unidentified groups, and miscellaneous. The collection consists of black-and-white and color photographs and negatives taken at Cleveland music halls, as well as some promotional materials for local artists, concerts, radio stations, record distributors, and venues. Prominent artists featured in this collection include: Louis Armstrong, LaVern Baker, Count Basie, James Brown, Ruth Brown, Ray Charles, Bill Doggett, the Drifters, the Four Tops, Aretha Franklin, Alan Freed, Bill Haley and the Comets, Roy Hamilton, Lionel Hampton, Mahalia Jackson, Louis Jordan, Jerry Lee Lewis, Frankie Lymon, Memphis Slim, Rick Nelson, the O'Jays, the Platters, Lloyd Price, the Temptations, Joe Tex, Martha and the Vandellas, Dinah Washington, and Jackie Wilson. Cleveland venues/locations featured include the Ankara, Band Box, the Birdland Lounge, Cabin Club, Carlton House, Cleveland Arena, Club Manhattan, Club Trinidad, Cotton Club, Gus's Show Bar Lounge, Lake Glen Country Club, the Lancer, Leo's Casino, the Lorain Armory, Masonic Temple, the Mirror Show Bar, Music Box, Pla-mor Ballroom, the Sheraton-Cleveland, Statler Hotel, and the Wheel Lounge. These materials provide rich insight to the R&B, jazz, and rock performers of the 1950s and 1960s, but more specifically to the local Cleveland music community of that time. Handwritten notes in pencil found on the backs of any photographs were taken by the processing archivist during a meeting on January 9, 2013 with local jazz historian Joe Mosbrook; retired Cleveland Public Library music librarian Bill Anderson; George Hendricks of the vocal group, the Hesitations; Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum employees Beverly Flowers and Howard Kramer; and retired Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum President and CEO Terry Stewart. Extended notes included for some of the artists and venues are the result of research conducted for the Library and Archives' exhibit, "Through the Lens of Jimmy Baynes: Cleveland Rock and Roll History, 1950s-1960s" (February-April 2013).
Baynes, Jimmy
Custodial History
The Jimmy Baynes Collection (Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum Collection) was purchased by the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, Inc. from Steve Carl in 2009 and 2011.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Patrons must sign the Acknowledgment of Legal Responsibilities and Privacy Rights statement on the Researcher Registration form before using this collection. Consult the Library and Archives in advance of your visit to ensure access to these materials is available.
Bibliography
All Music Guide. Accessed February 4, 2013. http://www.allmusic.com/.
A.M. Richard Fine Art. "Polaroid: Instant Joy." News release. June 2010.
Doo-Wop: Biography, Groups and Discography. Accessed February 4, 2013. http://doo-wop.blogg.org/.
Gart, Galen, comp. and ed. Rhythm and Blues in Cleveland, 1955 Edition. Winter Haven, FL: Big Nickel Productions, 2003.
Kitchen Sisters. "Walkin' Talkin' Bill Hawkins: Searching For My Father's Voice." Lost and Found Sound. NPR, 1999. Accessed January 25, 2013. http://www.npr.org/programs/lnfsound/stories/991217.stories.html.
Mosbrook, Joe. Jazzed in Cleveland. 1996-1998. Accessed January 18, 2013. http://www.cleveland.oh.us/wmv_news/#JAZZED.
Mosbrook, Joe. Cleveland Jazz History, 2nd ed. Cleveland, Ohio: Northeast Ohio Jazz Society, c2003.
"Venues." Buckeye Beat. Accessed February 1, 2013. http://www.buckeyebeat.com/venuesframe.html.
Wolff, Carlo. Cleveland Rock and Roll Memories: True and Tall Tales of the Glory Days, Told by Musicians, DJs, Promoters, and Fans Who Made the Scene in the '60s, '70s, and '80s. Cleveland, OH: Gray and Co., c2006.
Biographical Note
Following the lively Cleveland music scene from the 1940s into the 2000s was railway postal clerk James Hamilton Baynes, Jr. (July 12, 1922-September 9, 2010). "Jimmy" was the oldest of 11, growing up on East 43rd and East 87th Streets in Cleveland. He learned to play the piano from his mother and, somewhere along the way, also picked up the harp and a passion for photography. He is remembered for his dark suits, his smile, and, of course, his camera.
Baynes supplemented his weekly paycheck by photographing local events in the African-American community. He would snap Polaroids of the people featured in and attending the events and sell the instant images for $5.00 each. Though Baynes was not a trained photographer, the images he created over six decades—whether of weddings, beauty competitions, burlesque shows, or live music performances—provide an authentic and candid glimpse into African-American life, music, and culture in Cleveland. Throughout the years, Baynes’ photographs appeared in local magazines and newspapers, such as the Call and Post. From June 19 to July 31, 2010, Baynes' photos were exhibited at the A.M. Richard Fine Art Gallery in Brooklyn, New York, in the show, Polaroid: Instant Joy, alongside images by famous artists William Wegman, Ellen Carey, and Chuck Close. The gallery's press release for the exhibit called Baynes' photographs of ladies out for a night on the town in 1960s Cleveland, "deceivingly modest" and "beautiful."
Separated Materials
Some items are on exhibit. These items are noted at the file level. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
Related Materials
Additional photographs by Jimmy Baynes can be found in the following collections in this repository: LaMont Robinson Collection. Related materials providing content on local Cleveland jazz and R&B artists and venues may be found in other collections that constitute a part of the Northeast Ohio Popular Music Archives.
5 Royales; Adams, Faye; Ankara (Nightclub); Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971; Baker, LaVern; Basie, Count, 1904-1984; Baynes, Jimmy; Boles, Thomas, baritone saxophonist; Brown, Clarence, 1924-2005; Brown, James, 1933-2006; Brown, Ruth, 1928-2006; Burton, James, 1939-; Cabin Club (Nightclub: Cleveland, Ohio); Carl, Steve; Carlton House (Cleveland, Ohio); Charles, Ray, 1930-2004; Chic-a-Dee; Cleveland Arena; Club Manhattan (Nightclub); Club Trinidad (Nightclub: Cleveland, Ohio); Comets (Musical group); Cooper, Joe, drummer; Cotton Club (Nightclub: Cleveland, Ohio); Cotton Club (Nightclub: Washington, D.C.); Davis, Eddie, 1922-1986; Davis, Kenny, trumpet player; Doggett, Bill, 1916-1996; Drifters (Musical group); Evans, Russell, guitarist; Ford, Scotty; Four Tops (Musical group); Franklin, Aretha; Freed, Alan; Haley, Bill, 1925-1981; Hamilton, Roy; Hampton, Lionel; Haynes, Phillis; Heard, Fats; Hendricks, George, vocalist; Honeytones (Musical group); Jackson, Lawrence Jacktown; Jackson, Mahalia, 1911-1972; James, Jimmy, musician; Jenkins, Duke; Jordan, Louis, 1908-1975; King, B.B.; Landers, Jimmy; Leo's Casino (Nightclub: Cleveland, Ohio); Lewis, Jerry Lee; Lymon, Frankie; Memphis Slim; Metrotones (Musical group); Montclairs (Vocal group); Moondog and Band (Musical group); Music Box (Nightclub: Cleveland, Ohio); Nelson, Rick, 1940-1985; Northeast Ohio Popular Music Archives; Norwood, Helen; O'Jay, Eddie; O'Jays (Musical group); Overbea, Danny; Pearson, Lloyd; Platters (Musical group); Price Sisters; Price, Lloyd; Ragland, Lou; Raye, Jimmie; Reed, Lula; Richards, Karin; Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum Collection; Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum; Shirley and Lee (Musical group); Smith, Dottie, vocalist; Staton, Dakota; Stokes, Carl; Teenagers (Musical group); Tex, Joe, 1933-1982; Thompson, Hugh, pianist; Tolliver, Kim; Vandellas (Musical group); Walkin' Talkin' Bill Hawkins; Washington, Dinah, 1924-1963; Watts, Lou; Wilson, Jackie; Wilson, Ralph, saxophonist; Wilson, Teddy, 1912-1986; Yancy, Joe, bassist; Admission tickets; Business cards; Invitations; Mass media and publicity; Matchbooks; Menus; Music-halls; Negatives (photographic); Opal (Cleveland, Ohio); Photographs; Photography; Popular music radio stations--Ohio--Cleveland--Periodicals; Printed ephemera; Radio personalities--Ohio--Cleveland; Rock concerts--Ohio--Cleveland; Rock musicians--Ohio--Cleveland--Pictorial works
- Series I: Jimmy Baynes, undated
  Scope and Contents
  Series I: Jimmy Baynes, undated, includes a photograph of Baynes with his camera equipment, a business card, and an empty photograph mat promoting Baynes' photography business.
  Separated Materials
  Some items are on exhibit. These items are noted at the file level. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Baynes, Jimmy, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Undated black-and-white Polaroid photograph of Jimmy Baynes on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
- Series II: Artists, 1953-1973, 1983, undated
  Series II: Artists spans the years 1953 to 1973 and 1983 and includes undated materials. The bulk of the series contains black-and-white and color photographs and negatives of some of the most popular R&B artists of the late-1950s and 1960s, as well as local Cleveland musicians, business owners, other entertainers (e.g., dancers, comedians, disc jockeys), and politicians from the same time period. Please note that many of the folder dates reflect the date the film was processed, not necessarily the date of the performance. Most images are taken at Cleveland-area venues, including the Arena, the Band Box, Birdland Lounge, Lake Glen Country Club, Leo's Casino, the Lorain Armory, Masonic Temple, the Music Box, Pla-mor Ballroom, the Sheraton-Cleveland, and the Statler Hotel; identified exceptions include Alan Freed (Akron), and Sallie Blair (Cotton Club, Washington, D.C.). High profile artists featured include Louis Armstrong, LaVern Baker, Count Basie, James Brown, Ruth Brown, Ray Charles, the Drifters, the Four Tops, Aretha Franklin, Alan Freed, Bill Haley and the Comets, Roy Hamilton, Lionel Hampton, Mahalia Jackson, Louis Jordan, B.B. King, Jerry Lee Lewis, Frankie Lymon, Rick Nelson, the O'Jays, the Platters, Lloyd Price, the Temptations, the Vandellas, Dinah Washington, and Jackie Wilson. The bulk of the images are of live performances, but there are also more candid photos from backstage and of the audience in attendance at these events. In addition to photographic materials, the series also contains a few business cards for local talent. The files are arranged alphabetically by artist/group name. Within the files, the photographs are arranged chronologically, with undated materials at the end.
  - 5 Royales, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Faye, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    General note
    Inscribed to Jimmy Baynes.
  - Armstrong, Louis, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baker, LaVern, circa 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    One photo is autographed.
  - Bandmasters, circa 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    At the Music Box, which was located downstairs on Euclid Avenue, between 105th and 107th Streets.The Bandmasters were Joe Yancy, George Hendricks (Hesitations), and Lou Ragland.
    Item on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Basie, Count, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    A couple of images include singer Joe Williams.
  - Blackshaw, Sam, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    With unidentifed female singer.
  - Blair, Sallie, 1956 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Color photograph of Blair on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
    At the Cotton Club, Washington, D.C. One of the photographs is stapled into a Club 77 (7541 Kinsman Rd, Cleveland, Ohio) promotional photograph mat. Inscribed to Jimmy Baynes. Blair was a big-voiced, blues and ballads singer who had a moment in the late 1950s recording for Bethlehem. She never attained widespread popularity but was especially known for her performances of love songs.
  - Brown, Clarence "Gatemouth", undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brown, James, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Ruth, 1955 April 8, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    One photograph is inscribed to Jimmy Baynes.
  - Bryant, Sammy, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Charles, Ray, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chic-a-Dee, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Souvenir photograph for a show featuring Ray Charles and the Raelets at the Pla-mor Ballroom, 10626 Cedar Ave, Cleveland, Ohio. Chic-a-Dee was a locally popular swing piano and organ player, who the Call and Post called, “potentially one of the greatest entertainers to sell their wares locally.” Throughout the 1950s, he could be found performing at Jack’s Musical Bar (6608 Cedar Road), the Paddock Musical Bar (1600 Superior Avenue), Club 77 (7541 Kinsman Road) and Club Trinidad (10607 Superior Avenue).
  - Cooper, Joe, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Left to Right: unidentified (trumpet, trombone), Ace Carter, "Weasel" Parker, unidentified (drums), Joe Cooper
  - Davis, Eddie, 1957 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Doggett, Bill, 1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dorsey, Lee, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    At the Music Box. In this photograph, Dorsey was likely performing the song, “Ride your Pony,” with the line “(Pull out your pistol yeah) / Now get ready, now shoot / Shoot shoot.”
  - Drifters, circa 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Pictured (left to right): David Baughan, Gerhart Thrasher, Bill Pinkney, Andrew Thrasher, Jimmy Oliver. This is a transitional line up that existed between Clyde McPhatter’s departure for a solo career and Ben E. King’s arrival. The Drifters were inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame in 1988.
    Black-and-white 8" x 10" photograph on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Edsels, 1959 July 15 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fats Heard Combo, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Black-and-white photograph of the Fats Heard Combo filming at WEWS-TV on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
    Eugene “Fats” Heard began drum lessons while attending Cleveland’s Outhwaite Junior High School. After Central High School, where he was a member of the marching band and orchestra, Heard studied at the Cleveland Institute of Music. Heard was most popular during the 1950s, playing with Lionel Hampton’s band after WWII and with the Erroll Garner Trio beginning in 1953. Towards the end of the 1950s, Heard left Garner to spend more time with his family—touring occasionally with Sarah Vaughn, Teddy Wilson, and Carmen McRae—but spending most of his time operating the Modern Jazz Room near old Central Market.
  - Five Quails, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Black-and-white Polaroid photograph on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
    Art Kirkpatrick quit the Hepsters in 1955 to form his own group with Billy Strawbridge, Billy Fulgham, Donald Brown and James Williams, the Five Quails, who appeared regularly at the Rose Room at the Hotel Majestic (East 55th Street) and weekly on the Duke Jenkins Show, a weekly television show at Cleveland’s WEWS-TV Channel 5. They played local haunts like the Pla-mor (10626 Cedar Avenue), the Spaghetti Inn (at Wade Park) and the Keith Theater (105th Street and Euclid Avenue).
  - Ford, Scotty, undated (Box 1, Folder 24a)
  - Four Coins, March 28-March 30 (Box 1, Folder 24b)
  - Four Tops, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    At Leo's Casino.
  - Franklin, Aretha, 1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Freed, Alan, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    In Akron.
  - Grady, Shirley, Carlos Artega, Elizabeth Oliver (left to right), undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Haley, Bill, and the Comets, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    At the Cleveland Arena.
  - Hamilton, Roy, 1956, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    At the Band Box--one of many nightclubs in the University Circle area, including the Sky Bar, the Mirror Show Bar, Jack’s Place, Club 100 and the Town Casino.
    Black-and-white 8" x 10" photograph of Roy Hamilton with Ralph Wilson on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Hampton, Lionel, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Hawkins, Ken, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Left to Right: Harry Hanson, unidentified, Marv Johnson (Motown), unidentified, unidentified, Ken Hawkins
  - Haynes, Phillis, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    At the Music Box. Haynes was the owner of the Pinwheel Lounge (East 106th Street). The Pinwheel was a major club for soul acts, where both local and out of town acts performed. The Pinwheel was a popular venue for performing artists, as Haynes was not only the owner but a perfomer herself, so she treated the talent very well.
    Color photograph of Phillis Haynes on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Honeytones, 1955 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    In Akron, Ohio.
  - Jackson, Lawrence "Jacktown", undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
    One photograph includes an unidentified male vocal group.
  - Jackson, Mahalia, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - James, Jimmy, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Jenkins, Duke, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Duke Jenkins—originally from Canton, Ohio—and his orchestra arrived in Cleveland from Chicago in May 1952 to succeed Ralph Wilson at the Rose Room of the Majestic Hotel (East 55th Street); a gig that Jenkins and his crew maintained for five years. The group’s Thursday night jam sessions brought in musicians from all over the country. The Duke Jenkins Show, a weekly television show at Cleveland’s WEWS-TV Channel 5, was in production from 1955 to 1956. The show, which played on all three Cleveland television stations on Saturdays at 12:30 p.m., featured the group playing R&B, mambo, standards and pop ballads, with the vocal group, the Five Quails, and two guest acts each week, usually a touring jazz artist.
    Black-and-white 8" x 10" photograph of the Duke Jenkins Show, and black-and-white photograph of Duke Jenkins and his orchestra performing at the Rose Room, on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Jordan, Louis, 1953, 1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    One photograph includes Dottie Smith.
  - King, B.B., undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Landers, Robert, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    A couple of the images include "Rubber Legs" Lee. Landers and Lee were a musical comedy team.
  - Lewis, Jerry Lee, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Lymon, Frankie, and the Teenagers, circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    At the Cleveland Arena, most likely during the Biggest Rock 'n Roll Show of '56.
  - Lynn, Terry, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    At the Lake Glen Country Club, Cleveland, Ohio. Inscribed to Jimmy Baynes.
  - Memphis Slim, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Metrotones, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Includes Lawrence Jacktown Jackson on drums and Don Banks on guitar.
  - Mills Brothers, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Promotional photograph. Inscribed.
  - Montclairs, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    One photograph includes Little Eddie Woods.
  - Moondog and Band, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Business card.
  - Nelson, Rick, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    At the Cleveland Arena. With James Burton.
  - Norwood, Helen, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - O'Jay, Eddie, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Disc jockey at WSRS.
  - O'Jays, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Overbea, Danny, circa 1955 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    With Ralph Wilson and his combo.
  - Platters, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Price, Lloyd, 1961 March 29 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    At the Lorain Armory. One photograph includes baritone saxophonist Thomas Boles.
  - Price Sisters, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    At the Music Box.
  - Ragland, Lou, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Photograph also includes Billy Blackshaw on drums, Kenny Davis on trumpet, Lloyd Pearson on saxophone, and Russell Evans (O'Jays) on guitar.
  - Raye, Jimmie, circa 1961 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Reed, Lula, 1958 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Richards, Karin, 1958 January 17 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Shirley and Lee, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Fan club card.
  - Smith, Dottie, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    This image is cropped from the photograph that appears in the Louis Jordan file of Jordan with Smith. Autographed by Smith.
  - Spencer, Nate, undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Pictured with Duke Jenkins on piano.
  - Staton, Dakota, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Stokes, Carl, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
    At the Sheraton-Cleveland. Stokes was the 51st mayor of Cleveland.
  - Temptations, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    One photograph includes an image of Ken Hawkins.
  - Tex, Joe, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    At Hotel Statler, which was located at Euclid Ave and E 12th St, Cleveland, Ohio.
  - Thompson, Hugh, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tolliver, Kim, 1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Soul singer Kim Tolliver was born in Lebanon, Tennessee, but spent her formative years in Cleveland’s Hough neighborhood. She built a reputation with dramatic interpretations of blues and soul songs. Gigging for years before recording her first single, she became known as “Cleveland’s answer to Tina Turner.” She cut her first album, Passing Clouds, on Fantasy Records as Kimberly Briggs in 1972. She recorded her second LP, Come and Get Me, on Chess Records as Kim Tolliver. Neither label promoted the LPs, and they were quickly forgotten. Though her recordings were not popular, she continued to be active in local clubs like the Music Box and Gleason’s (5219 Woodland Avenue). In one photograph, Tolliver appears with husband Rex Robinson; together, they were known as the musical act the "Lovers."
    Color photograph of Kim Tolliver, circa 1966, on exhibit. Consult the Library and Archives staff in advance of your visit for additional information.
  - Vandellas, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Wain, Norman, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Disc jockey on WDOK.
  - "Walkin' Talkin'" Bill Hawkins, 1955 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    In 1948 Bill Hawkins, a former Pullman Porter, became Cleveland's first black disc jockey introducing rhythm and blues, gospel, jazz, and rock and roll. Broadcasting live from the window of his record shop on 105th and Cedar, Walkin' Talkin' Bill Hawkins became a local celebrity. Over the next decade, Hawkins was heard on WJS, WHK, WDOK and WSRS--sometimes all in the same day. He was widely imitated and influenced a generation of DJs--including "Moondog" Alan Freed.
  - Washington, Dinah, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Includes promotional photograph mat for the Birdland Lounge, 748 Prospect Ave, Cleveland, Ohio, which contains two flyers for "Jazz-A-Rama" at Shaker-Lee Hall, 3946 Lee Rd.
  - Watts, Louis, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    At the Music Box. Watts, an R&B artist who was born without arms, often performed "For Your Precious Love," which, combined with an introductory monologue, brought tears to the majority of his audiences.
  - Wells, Billy, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    With unidentified male vocal group.
  - Wilson, Carl, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Wilson, Jackie, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    At the Play-mor.
  - Wilson, Ralph, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)